# **DAVID JAMES**

# Software Engineer

## **CONTACT**

+44 7812 163982

✓ dvdjms@hotmail.com

david-james-2b949979

github.com/dvdjms

Edinburgh EH12 5DH

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## Languages

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Python
- Java
- C#
- HTML & CSS

# **Technologies**

- Django
- Flask
- Express
- React
- Spring
- ASP.net
- PostgreSQL
- Styled-Components

#### Other

- Git & GitHub
- Command Line Tools
- AWS Services

#### **PROFILE**

Software engineer with skills in frontend and backend technologies. Transitioned from careers in accounting and teaching through CodeClan's Software Development course. Experienced in deploying cloud-based applications and integrating platforms to deliver reliable, scalable technology solutions through both volunteer and freelance work.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer**

July 2024 to present

Kontroll Solutions, Edinburgh

- Implemented API integration between Infraspeak and Odoo platforms, streamlining product, stock level synchronization, and account journals.
- Used webhooks and polling techniques to keep data in sync across platforms.
- Applied AWS services (Lambda, API Gateway, EventBridge, DynamoDB, Secrets Manager, and SNS) to deliver scalable cloud-based solutions.

# **Software Engineer – Volunteer**

Aug 2023 to present

Scottish Tech Army, Edinburgh

- Automated project data and location pins on the STA website, using APIs
  (Jira, Google Maps, and postcode.io) to improve project visibility and access.
- Created an AWS Lambda function to populate DynamoDB with Jira project data, enhancing the STA Volunteer App's functionality.
- Gained training in AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK) and successfully deployed cloud solutions.

#### **Contact Tracer - Test and Protect Scotland**

Oct 2020 to Sep 2022

NHS Lothian, Edinburgh

- Conducted in-depth interviews with Covid-19 positive cases. Identified contacts, high risk situations, public health concerns and infection patterns.
- Supporting the rest of the team, sharing knowledge, experience, and best practice to support improvements to overall program.

## **English Teacher**

May 2014 to Aug 2021

Whales English, Beijing, China (Online) / Wall Street English, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam (Onsite) / Various Academies, South Korea (Onsite)

- Taught students of all ages and levels in class and social club settings.
- Self-prepared lessons and interactive activities to target receptive and productive skills, providing individual attention, assessment, and feedback.
- Demonstrated strong relationship-building and effective leadership.

#### **EDUCATION**

MA International Communication University of Leeds

BSc (Hons) Psychology Open University

BA (Hons) Media Studies De Montfort University

#### **CAREER MOTIVATION**

Technology is not just my career. It's my passion. I am driven by the desire to create solutions that make a difference.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

- Learning new technologies.
- Independent travel to Europe, Asia, and North & South America.
- Hiking and adventure.
- World Cinema.

#### **Treasury Accountant**

Jul 2007 to Jan 2014

Avison Young, Birmingham

- Key performer in a highly pressurised target driven environment to reconcile high profile accounts with up to £70 million of monthly transactions.
- · Proven abilities in investigating, analysing, and problem solving.
- Resolved complex and challenging problems entailing in-depth investigation.
- Made substantial contributions to improve team efficiency and effectiveness.
- Collaborated with internal and external stakeholders to deliver results.

#### **TRAINING**

# CodeClan

Sep 2022 to Feb 2023

Comprehensive 16-week programming course. SQA Accredited (Level 8). With over 800 hours of practical coding, individual and groups projects, and expert-led tuition. Included OOP, TDD, UX design, agile methodologies, version control, command line, and pair-programming.

PROJECTS View Portfolio

# WeatherWise

Fully responsive Weather app for a user to search 45,000 cities and get 24 hour and 10-day weather forecasts, taking advantage of APIs from openweathermap.org and met.no.

- Python/Django/React
- GitHub: https://github.com/dvdjms/WeatherWise

## **Recipe Generator**

Full stack application using C# and ASP.net, with an Angular frontend. Leveraging OpenAI's ChatGPT API, it allows users to select ingredients from a drop-down menu and instantly generate recipes.

- C#/ASP.net/Angular
- GitHub: https://github.com/dvdjms/Recipe-AI

# **Learn Scotland**

Full stack React application about Scotland allowing a user to interact with quizzes, see scores on a leader board, and post comments. This included a multiple choice, drag & drop, and map location quiz.

- JavaScript/React/Express/Mongodb
- GitHub: https://github.com/dvdjms/Learn Scotland